前情提要
权力的游戏
I want you to tell me the truth about Joffrey.
我希望你告诉我乔佛里的真相
He's a monster.
他是个魔鬼
With the Tyrells beside us,
有了提利尔家族与我们联合
no one will think of rebelling for another century.
再过一百年也没人敢叛乱
Ser Dontos from House of Hollard
霍拉德家族的唐托斯爵士
Ser Meryn, help Ser Dontos to celebrate my Nameday
梅泰林爵士，灌死唐托斯爵士来庆祝我的命名日
It would be bad luck to kill a man on your nameday.
在您的命名日杀人很不吉利
You'll be my new fool.
你就当我的新弄臣吧
Thank you, Your Grace.
谢谢您，陛下
Do you know what it takes
你知道怎样才能
to unite
团结19个部落吗？
I told them we were all going to die.
我告诉他们如果不去南方
If we don't get out.
我们都会死
Let us go, my father will pay you whatever you want.
让我们走，无论你要什么，我父亲都会给
Enough to buy me a new head?
够我买个新脑袋吗？
无垢者！
杀了奴隶主
杀了士兵
We need to find Sansa Stark a husband.
我们需要给珊莎·史塔克找个丈夫
Tyrion will do as he's bid and will marry Ser Loras.
提利昂会履行他的职责，而你要嫁给洛拉斯爵士
- I am not some brood mare. - You're my daughter!
- 我不是什么种母马
- 你是我女儿！
My feelings for you have not changed.
我对你的感情没变
I'm not your lady, I'm you whore.
我不是你的夫人，我是你的妓女
He's a Crow. He'll stab us in the back.
他是个乌鸦，他会在背后捅死我们
Kill him.
杀了他
That's a fine little blade.
这把小剑真不错
Something wrong with your leg, boy?
你腿有问题吗，孩子？
You got to carry me.
你得背着我
Robb.
罗柏
The Lannisters send their regards.
兰尼斯特家族表示问候
Too late.
来不及了
You know I didn't have a choice.
你知道我别无选择
You know nothing, Jon Snow.
你什么都不知道，琼恩·雪诺
Your home.
你到家了
-=TLF字幕组=-
荣誉出品
♪ Game of Thrones 4x01 ♪ Two Swords Original Air Date on April 6, 2014
翻译：Lydia萌
翻译：Hello Agnes
翻译：versus
君临
King's Landing
翻译：潜潜小保
翻译：LordVader
校对：LordVader
特效：飞翔的鸡
统筹：饭离烨
龙石岛
DragonStone
恐怖堡
Dreadfort
临冬城
WinterFell
根据乔治·R·R·马丁著《冰与火之歌》改编
权利的游戏
第四季   第一集
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
电视剧编剧
戴维·贝尼奥夫 & D·B·威斯
导演
D·B·威斯
两柄剑
- Magnificent. - Mm-hmm.
精美绝伦
Looks fresh-forged.
像新铸的
It is.
确实
No one's made a Valyrian steel sword
自从瓦雷利亚浩劫之后
since the Doom of Valyria.
就没人能铸瓦雷利亚钢剑了
There are three living smiths
世上还有三名铁匠
who know how to rework Valyrian steel.
知道如何重铸瓦雷利亚钢
The finest of them was in Volantis.
其中手艺最好的就在瓦兰提斯
Came here to King's Landing at my invitation.
受我邀请来到了君临
Where did you get this much Valyrian steel?
你从哪弄到这么多瓦雷利亚钢的？
From someone who no longer had need of it.
从某个不再需要的人手里
You've wanted one of these in the family for a long time.
你一直都想在家族里添一柄这剑
- And now we have two. - Two?
- 而现在有了两柄
- 两柄？
The original weapon was absurdly large.
原来那把大得荒唐
Plenty of steel for two swords.
足够铸造两柄剑
Well, thank you. It's glorious.
谢谢您，非常精美
You'll have to train your left hand.
你必须练习用左手
Any decent swordsman knows how to use both hands.
所有像样的剑士双手都会用剑
You'll never be as good.
你不会再像以前一样厉害了
No.
不会了
But as long as I'm better than everyone else,
但只要我还比其他人出色
I suppose it doesn't matter.
我觉得就无所谓
You can't serve in the Kingsguard with one hand.
一只手没法效力御林铁卫
Where's that written? I can and I will.
哪写着的？我能，也会继续效力
The Kingsguard oath is for life.
御林铁卫的宣誓终生有效
The war is over. The king is safe.
战争结束了，国王安全了
The king is never safe.
国王永远不会安全
How many people in this city alone would love to see his head on a pike?
只这一座城里就有多少人想看他脑袋插在枪尖上？
Other knights protected the king while you were a prisoner.
你被俘的时候有其他骑士保护国王
They will continue to do so when you go home.
在你回家后他们也会继续效力
- Home? - You'll return to Casterly Rock
- 回家？
- 你要回凯岩城
<i>and rule in my stead.</i>
<i>代替我统治</i>
You are the Lord of Casterly Rock.
你才是凯岩城的公爵
I am the King's Hand. My place is here.
我是国王之手，我的职责在此
I don't expect to see the Rock again before I die.
我不指望死前还能看到凯岩城了
You know what they call me?
你知道他们叫我什么吗？
Kingslayer. Oathbreaker.
弑君者，背誓者
Man without honor.
没有荣誉的人
Now you want me to break another sacred vow.
你想让我再背弃一条神圣誓言
You won't be breaking anything.
你什么也不用背弃
There is a precedent to relieve a Kingsguard of his duties.
御林铁卫被免除职责是有过先例的
The king will exercise that prerogative.
国王会再次行使这项特权
- No. - No?
- 不
- 不？
No.
不
I don't believe I asked you a question.
我没有问你问题
There's my answer.
这就是我的答案
If you think your bloody honor comes before--
如果你认为你的狗屁荣誉更重要…
My bloody honor is beyond repair,
我什么狗屁荣誉都无法挽回了
but my answer is still no. I don't want Casterly Rock.
但我的答案仍然是“不”，我不想要凯岩城
I don't want a wife. I don't want children.
我不想要妻子，我不想要孩子
What do you want?
你想要什么？
Supper would be nice.
晚饭就行
For 40 years I've tried to teach you.
40年了，我一直努力教导你
If you haven't learned by now, you never will.
如果你现在还不开窍，那以后也不会了
Go.
去吧
<i>If serving as a glorified</i> <i>bodyguard</i>
<i>如果当个美其名的保镖</i>
is the sum of your ambition, go serve.
就是你的人生大志，那就当去吧
I suppose you want the sword back.
我想你会要回这把剑
Keep it.
留着吧
A one-handed man with no family needs
没有家室的独手男
all the help he can get.
需要多多帮助
How many Dornishmen does it take to fuck a goat?
操一只羊要几个多恩人？
Please don't.
拜托别
<i>Seems to me</i> <i>the smart place</i>
<i>我觉得，要接见旅行者</i>
<i>to meet travelers</i> <i>is in a tavern.</i>
<i>最好是在小酒馆</i>
That way, one party is late,
这样的话，错过一个聚会
the other party can drink some ale inside.
还有别的聚会可以蹭点酒喝
This is the Prince of Dorne we're waiting for,
我们等的是多恩的亲王
not one of your sellsword friends.
不是你那些佣兵朋友
If he's so damned important, how come they sent you to meet him?
如果他真特别重要，他们怎么会派你来接见？
There's bad blood between the Martells of Dorne
多恩的马泰尔家族
and the Lannisters of Casterly Rock. Has been for years.
与凯岩城的兰尼斯特家族向来不和
And just in case the Martells of Dorne
所以万一马泰尔家族
are looking to spill some Lannister blood,
想放了某个兰尼斯特的血
- it may as well be yours, eh? - No need for cynicism.
- 还是放你的比较好，是吧？
- 别冷嘲热讽了
I happen to be an accomplished diplomat.
我正巧是个熟练的外交家
Ah, here we are.
来了
<i>Can you read the sigils?</i>
<i>你认识那些徽章吗？</i>
Yellow balls?
一堆黄球？
Wild lemons on a purple field,
紫色底色上排列着柠檬
House Dalt of Lemonwood.
柠檬林的达特家族
A vulture grasping a baby in its talons, House Blackmont.
黑色秃鹰爪抓一个婴孩，布莱蒙家族
A crowned skull, the Manwoodys of Kingsgrave.
带金冠的白色骷髅，王冢城的曼伍笛家族
Boy knows his Dornish Houses.
这孩子挺了解多恩的家族
I need a sigil.
我需要一个徽章
And House Martell, a red sun pierced by a spear?
马泰尔家族，一柄贯穿红日的金枪
I don't see it, my lord.
我没看到，大人
Well met, my lords.
很高兴见面，大人们
His Grace King Joffrey welcomes you in his name.
以乔佛里陛下的名义欢迎您们
My lord father, the King's Hand, sends his greetings as well.
我的父亲大人，国王之手也向您们致以问候
I am Tyrion Lannister of Casterly Rock,
我是凯岩城的提利昂·兰尼斯特
Master of Coin.
财政大臣
Forgive me.
原谅我
I don't see Prince Doran in your company.
我没有看到道朗亲王随行
The prince's health forces him to remain at Sunspear.
亲王身体抱恙，只能留在阳戟城
He sends his brother Prince Oberyn
他派来了他的弟弟奥伯伦亲王
<i>to attend the royal</i> <i>wedding in his stead.</i>
<i>来代替他参加皇室婚礼</i>
Yes, the king will be delighted to enjoy the company
好的，国王会很高兴能有
of a warrior as renowned as Prince Oberyn
如奥伯伦亲王这样有名望的武士前来
at his wedding feast.
参加他的喜宴
Will he?
是吗？
And where is Prince Oberyn?
那奥伯伦亲王在哪里？
Arrived before dawn.
黎明前就到了
Not a man for welcome parties,
他不爱参加欢迎仪式
<i>our prince.</i>
<i>我们的亲王</i>
Very well. My lords, these fine men from the City Watch
很好，大人们，这些守备队的精锐护卫
will escort you to your quarters in the Red Keep.
会护送您们到红堡的住处
You must be weary after such a long journey.
如此长途跋涉您们一定很疲惫了
Some accomplished diplomacy that was.
这就是熟练的外交家
Now where?
现在去哪？
We must find Prince Oberyn before he kills somebody
我们必须在奥伯伦亲王杀某人
or several somebodies.
或很多人前找到他
How do you plan on finding a single Dornishman in a city this big?
城市这么大，你打算怎么找一个多恩人？
You're famous for fucking half of Westeros.
假设你号称操过一半维斯特洛人
You just arrived at the capital after two weeks of bad roads,
你刚刚颠簸了两个星期到达王都
where would you go?
你会去哪？
I'd probably go to sleep, but I'm getting old.
我可能会去睡，不过我老了
Look at this one.
看看这个
How lovely is she?
她多可爱啊？
Beautiful.
真美
But pale.
但是太苍白
They like them pale in the capital.
王都的人就喜欢苍白的
Shows they don't work the fields.
说明她们不在外干活
Do I frighten you?
我吓着你了？
You like?
你喜欢吗？
Timid. Timid bores me.
太害羞，害羞的没意思
You're a bit of mischief, aren't you?
你是个小顽皮，是吗？
I think she likes you.
我觉得她喜欢你
She has good taste.
她品味不错啊
You're not timid, are you?
你可一点也不害羞啊
Not timid.
真不害羞
Do you like women?
你喜欢女人？
When they look like her, my lord.
只喜欢她的这样的，大人
This one will do nicely.
这个会很不错
<i>Very good, my lady.</i>
<i>非常好，夫人</i>
Oh, I'm not a lady.
我可不是夫人
A term of courtesy in this establishment.
只是这里的恭维话
A lie anywhere.
在哪说都是谎话
Why not use the right words?
为什么不直说？
I'm a bastard.
我是个杂种
She is a whore. And you're what?
她是妓女，你是什么？
A procurer.
拉皮条的
Any of the others?
还要其他人吗？
The two girls can leave.
这两个女孩可以走了
You stay.
你留下
I'm afraid I'm not an offer, my lord.
恐怕我不供娱乐，大人
Everyone who works for Littlefinger is an offer.
所有给小指头当差的都供娱乐
Take off your clothes. We'll be here a while.
把衣服脱了，我们会在这里待一会
- My lord. - I am a prince, boy.
- 大人
- 我是亲王，小子
Have you ever been with a prince?
你跟亲王搞过吗？
Can't say I have.
没有
I'm wildly expensive.
我身价很高的
Take off your clothes.
把衣服脱了
Which way do you like it?
你想怎么来？
My way.
按我的方式来
<i>♪ And so he spoke</i> <i>and so he spoke ♪</i>
<i>♪ 他这样说，他这样说 ♪</i>
<i>♪ That Lord of Castamere ♪</i>
<i>♪ 卡斯特梅的领主 ♪</i>
- <i>♪ And now the rains... ♪</i> - Oberyn.
- <i>♪ 雨水在大厅哭泣… ♪</i>
- 奥伯伦，不要
<i>♪ With no one there</i> <i>to hear ♪</i>
<i>♪ 内里却无人影 ♪</i>
♪ Yes, not the rains weep o'er his hall ♪
♪ 雨水在大厅哭泣 ♪
♪ And not a soul to hear. ♪
♪ 内里却无魂灵 ♪
You lost, friend?
你迷路了，朋友？
Forgive me for staring.
很抱歉盯着你们看
I don't see many Lannisters where I'm from.
我们那里很少有兰尼斯特家的人
I don't see many Dornishmen in the capital.
我在首都也很少看到多恩人
We don't like the smell.
我们不喜欢这种气味
- Come with me, lover. - Gods, look at this one.
- 跟我来，亲爱的
- 天哪，看看她
Sirs, if you follow me, I'll arrange for a private room.
爵士，跟我来，我为您安排单间
Why are you wasting a woman like this on a Dornishman?
为什么把这么一个美人让多恩人糟蹋？
Bring him a shaved goat and a bottle of olive oil.
给他找头剃了毛的山羊和橄榄油
Do you know why all the world hates a Lannister?
你知道为什么全世界都恨兰尼斯特吗？
You think your gold and your lions
你们以为你们的金子，狮子
and your gold lions make you better than everyone.
金狮子让你们高人一等
May I tell you a secret?
我能跟你说个秘密吗？
You're not a golden lion.
你不是金狮子
You're just a pink little man
你就是个没用的白人
who is far too slow on the draw.
拔剑迟缓
Longsword is a bad option in close quarters.
长剑在近身战中不是明智的选择
When I pull my blade, your friend starts bleeding.
我一拔剑，你的朋友就得流血了
Quite a lot, I'm afraid. So many veins in the wrist.
恐怕会流很多，手腕上有这么多血管
He'll live if you get him help straightaway.
你立刻帮他，他就能活命
So, decisions.
那么，决定吧
Prince Oberyn, forgive the intrusion.
奥伯伦王子，原谅我不请自来
We heard there might be...
我们听说这里可能会有…
...trouble.
…麻烦
Apologies, my love.
抱歉，亲爱的
I'm here to welcome you to the capital.
欢迎你来到首都
Ellaria Sand, my paramour.
艾拉莉亚·沙德，我的情人
The king's own Uncle Imp.
这位是国舅小恶魔
Tyrion, son of Tywin Lannister.
提利昂，泰温·兰尼斯特之子
If there's anything I can do to make your stay--
有任何…我可以使你…
What are you? His hired killer?
你是谁？他雇佣的杀手？
It started that way, aye. Now I'm a knight.
那是以前，现在我是骑士
How did that come to pass?
你怎么做到的？
Killed the right people, I suppose.
杀了该杀的人，我猜
We'll need a few more girls. Girls, yes?
我们还需要一些姑娘，行吗？
You don't partake?
你不一起来？
Oh, I partook. Now I'm married.
以前来过，现在我结婚了
Prince Oberyn, if I may, a word in private?
奥伯伦王子，我们能否单独谈谈？
Seems I visited the Lannister brothel by mistake.
看样子我不该来兰尼斯特的妓院
- Oh, they take all kinds. - Even Dornishmen.
- 他们接待各种客人
- 包括多恩人
The king is very grateful that you traveled all
国王对你远道而来参加他的婚礼
this way for his wedding.
十分感激
Let us speak truth here. Joffrey is insulted.
说实话吧，乔佛里受耻辱了
I am only the second son after all.
毕竟我只是次子
Well, speaking as a fellow second son,
同样作为次子
I have grown rather used to being the family insult.
我打小就是家族的耻辱
Why did you come to King's Landing, Prince Oberyn?
你为何来君临城，奥伯伦亲王？
I was invited to the royal wedding.
我受邀参加王室婚礼
I thought we were speaking truth.
我以为我们在开诚布公地谈
The last time I was in the capital was many years ago.
我上次来首都是好多年前了
Another wedding.
另一场婚礼
My sister Elia
我妹妹伊莉亚
and Rhaegar Targaryen, the Last Dragon.
和雷加·坦格利安，最后的真龙
My sister loved him. She bore his children.
我妹妹爱他，为他生了孩子
Swaddled them, rocked them, fed them at her own breast.
抱他们，哄他们，亲自哺乳
Elia wouldn't let the wet nurse touch them.
伊莉亚不让奶妈碰他们
And beautiful, noble Rhaegar Targaryen
美丽尊贵的雷加·坦格利安
left her for another woman.
却为了另一个女人离开了她
That started a war
挑起一场战争
and the war ended right here
那场战争就结束于此地
when your father's army took the city...
你父亲的军队攻下了这座城…
I wasn't actually present.
我当时不在
...and butchered those children.
…残杀了那些孩子
My nephew and niece.
我的侄子侄女
Carved them up and wrapped them in Lannister cloaks.
他们被切碎包在兰尼斯特的斗篷里
And my sister, you know what they did to her?
至于我妹妹，你知道他们对她做了什么吗？
I'm asking you a question.
我在问你
I've heard rumors.
我听到过传言
So have I.
我也是
The one I keep hearing is that Gregor Clegane the Mountain
我听到的是魔山格雷果·克里冈
raped Elia and split her in half
强奸了伊利亚，用他的剑
with his great sword.
把她劈成两半
I wasn't there. I don't know what happened.
我不在场，不知道发生了什么
If the Mountain killed my sister,
如果魔山杀了我妹妹
your father gave the order.
就是你父亲下的令
Tell your father I'm here.
告诉你父亲我来了
And tell him the Lannisters aren't the only ones who pay their debts.
告诉他不是只有兰尼斯特家的人有债必偿
Shh.
嘘
Shh. Shh.
嘘，嘘
They're dragons, Khaleesi.
它们是龙，卡丽熙
They can never be tamed.
无法被驯服
Not even by their mother.
即使是它们的母亲
- Ser Barristan. - Your Grace.
- 巴利斯坦爵士
- 女王陛下
Where's Daario Naharis?
达里奥·纳哈里斯在哪？
Where's Grey Worm?
灰虫子在哪？
Gambling, Your Grace.
赌博，陛下
Gambling?
赌博？
Mhysa. Mhysa. Mhysa...
弥莎，弥莎，弥莎…
How long have they been at it?
他们僵持多久了？
Since midnight, Your Grace.
半夜就开始了，陛下
Ser Worm is stronger than he looks.
蠕虫爵士比他看起来强壮
But I can see his arms beginning to shake.
但我能看出来他的手开始抖了
What's the prize to winning this stupid contest?
这场愚蠢的比赛奖品是什么？
The honor of riding by your side on the road to Meereen.
去弥林的路上跟您并驾而驱的荣耀
That honor goes to Ser Jorah and Ser Barristan
这荣耀属于乔拉爵士和巴利斯坦爵士
as neither of them kept me waiting this morning.
因为今早他们没有让我等
You two will ride in the rear guard and protect the livestock.
你们俩作后卫保护辎重
The last man holding his sword
最后一个拿剑的人
can find a new queen to fight for.
可以另寻明主了
你喜欢这个女孩？
很受挫吧
你不够聪明，达里奥·奥哈里斯
我宁愿自己没脑子
有两个蛋
You need to eat something.
你得吃点东西
Pigeon pie.
鸽子派
No, thank you.
不用，谢谢
Lemon cakes?
柠檬蛋糕？
No, thank you.
不用，谢谢
You love lemon cakes.
你爱吃柠檬蛋糕啊
Tell her she needs to eat.
跟她说她得吃点东西
My lady, you do need to eat.
小姐，你真的得吃点
I don't need to eat.
我不想吃
If I could have a moment alone with my wife.
请容我与我妻子独处一会
She needs to eat.
她得吃点东西
I can't let you starve.
我不能让你饿死
<i>I swore to protect you.</i>
<i>我发过誓会保护你</i>
My lady,
小姐
I am your husband. Let me help you.
我是你丈夫，让我来帮你
How can you help me?
你怎么帮我？
I don't know, but I can try.
我不知道，但我可以试试
I lie awake all night staring at the canopy
我整夜未眠盯着房顶
thinking about how they died.
想着他们如何死去
I could get you essence of nightshade to help you sleep.
我可以给你夜影之水帮助你入眠
Do you know what they did to my brother?
你知道他们对我哥哥做了什么吗？
How they sewed his direwolf's head onto his body?
他们怎么把冰原狼的头缝到他身上？
And my mother.
还有我母亲
They say they cut her throat to the bone
他们说他们割断她的喉咙
and threw her body in the river.
把她的遗体丢进河里
<i>What happened to your family</i> <i>was a terrible crime.</i>
<i>你们家族的遭遇</i><i>是很可怕的罪行</i>
I didn't know your brother.
我不了解你哥哥
He seemed like a good man, but I didn't know him.
他看上去是个好人，但我不了解他
<i>Your mother,</i> <i>on the other hand,</i>
<i>你母亲则不然</i>
<i>I admired her.</i>
<i>我敬仰她</i>
She wanted to have me executed,
她想处死我
but I admired her.
但我敬仰她
She was a strong woman.
她是个坚强的女人
And she was fierce
在保护她的孩子时
when it came to protecting her children.
她又可以很凶残
Sansa.
珊莎
Your mother would want you to carry on.
你母亲会希望你向前看
You know it's true.
你知道的
Will you pardon me, my lord?
失陪了，大人
I'd like to visit the godswood.
我想去神木林
Of course. Of course. Prayer can be helpful, I hear.
当然，听说做祷告会好一点
I don't pray anymore.
我不做祷告了
It's the only place I can go where people don't talk to me.
我不想听别人说话只能去那里了
My lion.
我的狮子
What are you doing?
你在做什么？
What does it look like I'm doing? Come here.
我看起来像在做什么？过来
How many times have I told you? You can't visit me here.
我跟你说过多少次了？你不能到这来找我
I know. I know.
我知道，我知道
We have come to a dangerous place.
我们身处险境
Have you forgotten me? Do you know how long it's been?
你忘记我了吗？你知道过了多久了吗？
Of course I haven't forgotten.
当然，我没忘记
I want you.
我想要你
Don't you want me?
你不想要我吗？
Things are a bit tense right now.
现在情势有点紧张
What things?
什么情势？
My nephew the king wants to murder me.
我侄子，国王想杀我
My wife hates me because my father murdered her family.
我妻子恨我，因为我父亲谋杀她整个家族
Oberyn Martell wants to murder everyone whose
奥柏伦马泰尔想杀了所有
last name is Lannister.
兰尼斯特家族的人
You need to relax.
你需要放松
Don't you want to relax?
你不想好好放松一下？
- What's wrong? - I told you.
- 到底怎么了？
- 我说了
- It's not a good time. - It's never a good time.
- 现在不合适
- 永远都不合适
- You have your child bride now. - Shae.
- 现在你有那个小姑娘当老婆了
- 雪伊
- Do you love her? - Love her?
- 你爱她吗？
- 爱？
I barely know her. She's a child.
我都不怎么了解她，她只是个小孩
- She despises me. - That's not an answer.
- 她看不起我
- 这不算回答
Of course I don't love her.
我当然不爱她
You tried to ship me away.
你想派船把我送走
Ship you away?
送走你？
Give me diamonds and make me disappear.
给我钻石然后让我永远消失
What in the world are you talking about?
你到底在说什么
If you want me to leave, just say it.
如果你想让我走，说一声就行了
- Say it! - Shh.
- 说啊！
- 嘘
I don't know what you're talking about.
我真的不知道你在说些什么
You want me to stay?
那你想让我留下？
A work of art, really.
真是件艺术品
The craftsmanship is excellent.
这手艺可真精妙
You like it so much,
既然你这么喜欢
you're welcome to chop off your own hand and take it.
不如把自己手剁了然后拿去用
Such an ingrate. I spent days with the goldsmith
真忘恩负义，我和金匠花了好几天
- getting the details just right. - Days?
- 才把细节做得这么恰到好处
- 几天？
Better part of an afternoon.
都是下午
There, how does that feel?
好了，感觉怎么样？
Uh...
呃…
a hook would be more practical.
如果是钩子的话更实用
Elegant, I think.
我觉这个更优雅
Thank you for your help with the other matter.
其它的事情也谢谢你帮忙了
- The symptoms have abated? - Gone completely.
- 症状缓和了吗？
- 已经都好了
I am in your debt, Maester Qyburn.
科本学士，我欠你人情
Not a maester, Your Grace, but happy to help
不是学士了，夫人，但只要我能帮忙
whenever I can.
任何时候都乐意效劳
Odd little man.
怪人
I've grown rather fond of him.
我越来越喜欢他了
He's quite talented, you know?
你知道吗，他很有才能
What symptoms?
哪些方面
Symptoms that are not your concern.
都是些你不关心的
You let him touch you?
你让他摸你了？
You jealous?
你嫉妒了？
I'm surprised.
只是惊讶
You never let Pycelle near you.
你没让派席尔近过身
You think I'd let that old lecher put his hands on me?
你觉得我会让那个老色鬼碰我？
He smells like a dead cat.
他的味道像死猫
<i>I'm not sure I've ever</i> <i>smelled a dead cat.</i>
我不确定我有没有闻过死猫
Well, they smell like Pycelle.
它们闻起来和派席尔一样
You drink more than you used to.
你喝酒比原来多了
- Yes. - Why?
- 没错
- 为什么？
Let's see, you started a brawl in the streets with Ned Stark
为什么？你在街上袭击奈德·史塔克
and disappeared from the capital.
然后从君临消失
My husband died in a tragic hunting accident.
我丈夫死于悲惨的打猎事故
It must have been traumatic for you.
你一定深受重创
My only daughter was shipped off to Dorne.
我唯一的女儿被船送去了多恩
<i>We suffered</i> <i>through a siege.</i>
我们被人围攻
A rather short siege.
短暂的围攻
A rather short siege that I didn't expect to survive.
真短，短到我都没想过能活下来
And now I'm marrying my eldest son
现在我要让长子
to a wicked little bitch from Highgarden
和从高庭来的邪恶的小婊子结婚
while I'm supposed to marry her brother,
我还被许配给了她哥哥
a renowned pillow biter. So...
公认的骗子，所以…
Father disowned me today.
爸已经不认我了
He can't disown you. You're all he's got.
他不能不认你，你是他的全部
You're forgetting Tyrion.
你忘了提利昂
You don't really plan on staying in the Kingsguard, do you?
你不会真想留在御林铁卫，对吧？
Staying in the Kingsguard means I live right here
留在御林铁卫意味着我能在这里
in the Red Keep with you.
在红堡陪你
- Not now. - I want--
- 现在不行
- 我想要
Not now? When? I've been back for weeks.
现在不行，那什么时候行？我已经回来几个星期了
- Something's changed. - Everything's changed.
- 有些事情变了
- 所有事情都变了
You come back after all this time with no apologies
你这么久才回来，还折了一只手
and one hand and expect everything to be the same?
连一声道歉都没有，还希望一切和原来一样？
What do you want me to apologize for?
你想让我为什么道歉？
For leaving me.
为离开我
You think I wanted to be taken prisoner?
你以为我想做囚犯？
Don't know what you wanted. You weren't here.
我不知道你想要什么，总之你不在这里
You left me alone.
你抛下我一个人
Every day I was a prisoner, I plotted my escape.
我在外面当着囚犯，每天都谋划着逃出来
Every day. I murdered people so I could be here with you.
我杀了人才能在这里和你相见
- You took too long. - I...
- 太久了
- 我…
- What are you saying? - I'm saying you took too long.
- 你到底在说什么？
- 我说你去了太久
- Come in. <i>- Go away.</i>
- 进来
- 出去
Forgive me, Your Grace.
抱歉，夫人
You told me to come at once if there was anything important.
您说如果有紧急事态就让我马上来
You plan on killing all the crows yourself?
你想单枪匹马杀了所有乌鸦？
Do you plan on sitting here scratching your balls till winter?
那你就一直坐那儿抓你的蛋蛋抓到冬天？
We wait for Mance's orders.
我们在等曼斯的命令
You sent a man over the Wall at the full moon.
满月时你派了一个人去长城
<i>If he's not back yet,</i> <i>he's not coming back.</i>
如果他还没回来那他就回不来了
<i>And what is it</i> <i>you want?</i>
你到底想要做什么？
March on Castle Black with just this lot?
带着这点人就想朝黑城堡进军？
Your pretty crow said 1,000 men are nesting there.
你那可爱的乌鸦说那儿有一千人驻守
Yeah, well, he's a liar.
他是个骗子
He is?
他是？
Shouldn't it be "he was"?
难道不应该是“他原来是”？
You said you put three arrows in him.
你说向他射了三支箭
I did.
没错
I've seen you slip a shaft through a rabbit's eye at 200 yards.
我曾见你把箭射进两百码外的兔子的眼睛
If that boy's still walking, it's 'cause you let him go.
如果他还能走，那是你放他走的
Thenns.
塞恩人
I fucking hate Thenns.
我真他妈讨厌塞恩人
Mance sent you?
曼斯让你们来的？
How did you find us?
你们怎么找到我们的？
You came from the south, not the north.
你们从南边来，不是北边
Took a detour.
我们绕了点路
Got some supper from a village down that way.
在路上的村子弄了点晚餐
<i>Why does the meat down here</i> <i>taste so much better</i>
为什么长城这边的肉…
than it does on our side of the Wall?
比我们那边的更好吃？
Help yourself.
请自便
Maybe everything's just better fed down here.
可能这里的东西都被喂养的挺好
Fat and lazy.
又胖又懒
Easier for us, hmm?
对我们来说容易多了，不是吗？
You didn't see us coming?
你们没看到我们过来？
Lost your warg?
你们的狼灵丢了？
And that baby crow you had with you,
还有你们的小乌鸦
lost him too?
也丢了？
I'll answer to Mance.
我只听从曼斯
I won't answer to you.
不听从你
She yours?
她是你的？
I'm not anybody's.
我不是任何人的
Too scrawny.
真瘦
Not like those crows at Castle Black.
不像黑城堡的那些乌鸦
<i>Think of them</i> <i>stuck in their larders</i>
想想他们被卡在储藏间里
stuffing their faces with ham and blood sausage
香肠和火腿吃的满脸都是
and stew, getting nice and fat
还能炖东西吃，变得又白又胖
and marbled.
长的五花肉
I know we've had our differences, Tormund,
我知道我们有些不同，托蒙德
but just one time before you die,
但在你死之前，你真的要尝尝乌鸦
you really ought to try crow.
就这一次
<i>Draw.</i>
拉箭
Loose.
放箭
<i>Last time I saw him,</i>
我最后一次见到他
<i>he was in the courtyard</i> <i>at Winterfell.</i>
是在临冬城的院子里
<i>He said,</i> <i>"Next time I see you,</i>
他说，下次我再见到你
<i>you'll be all in black."</i>
你就是守夜人了
I was jealous of Robb my whole life.
我一辈子都嫉妒罗柏
<i>The way my father</i> <i>looked at him,</i>
父亲看他的样子
<i>I wanted that.</i>
我嫉妒
He was better than me at everything--
他什么都比我强
fighting and hunting
战斗，打猎
and riding
骑马
and girls.
还有姑娘们
<i>Gods, the girls</i> <i>loved him.</i>
诸神啊，女孩们都喜欢他
I wanted to hate him, but I never could.
我想恨他，但我做不到
Sometimes I want to hate you.
有的时候，我想要恨你
Well, you're better than me at everything.
嗯，你什么都比我强
Except reading.
读书除外
They're-- they're ready for you.
他们…他们在等着你
He's wanted to hang me for a while. Now's his chance.
他一直想绞死我，现在机会来了
No one's going to hang you.
没人想绞死你
You've done nothing wrong.
你没做错任何事
I've done plenty wrong.
我的错太多了
So you admit you murdered Qhorin Halfhand?
所以你承认你谋杀了断掌科林
<i>I didn't murder him.</i>
不是谋杀
No? You put your sword
不是？你把你的剑…
through a brother of the Night's Watch.
挥向了守夜人兄弟
What do you call that?
你说说那是什么？
He wanted me to kill him.
他希望我杀死他
A bastard son of a traitor.
对背叛者的私生子
What would you expect?
你还能期待什么
The Halfhand believed our only chance
科林坚信，我们抵挡住曼斯的唯一机会
to stop Mance was to get a man inside his army.
就是在他的军队里安插一个人
Don't talk about the Halfhand as if you knew him.
不要这样说话，好像你很了解他
He was my brother.
他曾经是我兄弟
Then you'd know he'd do anything to defend the Wall.
那你应该知道为了镇守长城他会做任何事
The free folk would have boiled him alive, but letting me kill him...
自由民本可活活煮死他，但让我动手杀死他
<i>The free folk?</i> <i>Listen to him.</i>
- 自由民？
- 听听
He even talks like a wildling now.
他连说话都像个野人
Aye, I talk like a wildling. I ate with the wildlings.
是的，我像野人一样说话，我与野人一同吃饭
I climbed the Wall with the wildlings. I--
我与野人一同爬过长城
I laid with a wildling girl.
我…我还睡了一个野人姑娘
You admit to breaking your vows, then?
那你承认违背誓言了？
I do.
是的
The law is the law. The boy must die.
规矩就是规矩，这个小子必须死
If we beheaded every ranger who lay with a girl,
如果每一个与姑娘上床的游骑兵都得被砍头
the Wall would be manned by headless men.
守长城的就都是些无头者了
There's a difference between sneaking off
溜进鼹鼠城的妓院和与敌人上床
to the Mole's Town brothel and sleeping with the enemy.
这是不一样的
While we sit here
就在此时，我们坐在这里
debating which rules I broke,
争论我到底犯了哪一条规矩
Mance Rayder marches on the Wall with an army of 100,000.
曼斯·雷德正带着十万人的军队行进在长城上
Impossible.
这不可能
You can't get 50 wildlings together
哪怕有50个野人聚集起来
before they start killing each other.
他们就开始自相残杀了
100,000. He's united the Thenns,
有十万人，他联合了瑟恩人
<i>the Hornfoots,</i> <i>the ice-river clans.</i>
<i>霍恩福特人,和冰河族人</i>
He has giants fighting for him.
巨人也为他作战
Giants?
巨人？
Have you ever been beyond the Wall, ser?
你去过长城外面吗，长官？
I commanded the City Watch of King's Landing, boy.
我可是君临都城守备队的指挥，小子
And now you're here.
可你现在在这儿
You must not have been very good at your job.
那你一定干得不好
How dare you?!
你竟敢口出狂言？！
There's a band of wildlings south of the Wall already
已经有一小队野人到了长城南面
led by Tormund Giantsbane.
是“巨人克星托蒙德”带的队
I killed their warg and three others.
我杀了他们的狼灵和三名野人
They shot me full of arrows.
他们朝我射了一大把箭
Their orders are to attack Castle Black from the south
他们的任务是从南侧进攻黑城堡
when Mance hits it from the north.
曼斯则从北面进攻
The signal for the attack will be a bonfire.
进攻的信号就是篝火
Mance said it would be the greatest fire the North has ever seen.
曼斯说，这将是北方人见过最壮丽的篝火
<i>That's the truth.</i>
<i>这是实话</i>
All the truth.
都是实话
Do you intend to execute me or am I free to go?
你们要处决我，还是还我自由？
None of us are free.
这儿没人是自由的
We are men of the Night's Watch.
我们是守夜人
But we won't be taking your head today, Jon Snow.
但我们今天不会取你的脑袋，琼恩·雪诺
Go on.
走吧
I am acting commander here, Maester Aemon.
我才是这里的执行官，伊蒙学士
Yes, you are.
是的，你才是
And I don't trust the bastard.
我不信任这个私生子
He told the truth.
他说的是实话
And you always know when a man's telling a lie?
只要有人说谎，你都能辨别出来吗？
How did you acquire this magical power?
你这魔法是从哪儿学来的？
I grew up in King's Landing.
我可是在君临城长大的
<i>No. No.</i>
<i>不行，不行</i>
You're a queen, not an ox.
你可是皇后，又不是公牛
Your grandfather gave me a necklace
你爷爷曾送给我一条项链，跟这个一样
just like this one for my 51st nameday.
在我第51个命名日上
The wedding is in a fortnight, Grandmother.
两周后就要举行婚礼了，奶奶
You can't say no to everything.
你不能对所有事情都不满意
Nonsense. My little dears.
胡说！我的小宝贝
Go and speak to the jewelers of King's Landing.
去找君临城的珠宝匠
Tell them who you are, tell them who sent you.
告诉他们你们是谁，是谁派你们来的
The one who brings me the best necklace
谁找到最好的项链
will get to keep the next best.
就能得到第二好的那一条
The Margaery Tyrell who walks into the sept
玛格丽特·提利尔两周后要大婚
a fortnight from now will inspire 1,000 songs.
将会给上千首歌带来灵感
Now, how sad it will be if she's wearing rubbish like that.
要是她戴着这样的垃圾货色，该有多伤心
Perhaps I should just let Joffrey choose it for me.
也许我就该让乔佛里给我挑选一条
End up with a string of dead sparrow heads around my neck.
最后肯定是戴一串死麻雀的脑袋在脖子上
You watch that. Even here, even with me.
你瞧好了，他要是敢在这儿，在我面前这么做
My word.
我的天哪
My lady. My lady.
老夫人，小姐
Please pardon me for interrupting.
抱歉打扰了
My name is Brienne of Tarth.
我是塔斯的布蕾妮
We know who you are. We've heard all about you.
我们知道你是谁，久仰大名
But hearing is one thing.
但是耳听为虚
Aren't you just marvelous?
你真是太棒了
Absolutely singular.
绝对独一无二
I hear you knocked my grandson into the dirt
我听说你把我孙子打昏在地
like the silly little boy he is.
就好像他是个笨小孩
My lady, I know this is a very busy time for you,
小姐，我知道您现在非常忙
but if I could just have a moment.
但是能允许我耽误您一会儿吗？
You dare not refuse.
你怎能拒绝呢
A shadow?
影子？
A shadow with the face of Stannis Baratheon.
一个影子长着史坦尼斯·拜拉席恩的脸
I swear to you by all the gods it was Stannis.
我以诸神的名义向您发誓，那是史坦尼斯
He plunged his sword through Renly's heart
他把他的剑插进蓝礼的心脏
and disappeared.
然后就消失了
One day, my lady, I will avenge our king.
小姐，总有一天我会为我们的国王报仇
Joffrey is our king now.
现在乔佛里是我们的国王
I meant no offense.
我并无冒犯之意
And you've given none.
你并未冒犯
All the Kingsguard will be on duty, of course.
当然，所有御林铁卫都必须到位
Ser Boros will be stationed here.
柏洛斯爵士的岗位在这儿
Ser Preston will be stationed here
普莱斯特爵士的岗位在这儿
beside the primary entertainment.
在主乐队旁边
Your Grace?
陛下？
Yes, yes, one guard at the--
是的，可以，一个守卫，在…
the thing. Go on.
在那个地方，你们继续
Ser Meryn will guard Lady Margaery and Tommen.
马林爵士保护玛格丽特小姐和托曼
I've always guarded the king himself, my lord.
大人，我一直亲自保护国王
Ever since your absence.
在你离开的这段时间里
And I thank you for it, Ser Meryn.
为此我非常感谢，马林爵士
All very good. I don't expect any trouble.
非常好，我可不想有什么麻烦
The people love their king.
人们爱戴他们的国王
They know who keeps them fed.
他们知道是谁让他们填饱肚子
Margaery Tyrell, I've heard.
我听说是玛格丽特·提利尔
By my leave.
当我不在的时候
They know I saved the city. They know I won the war.
他们知道是我拯救了这座城市，是我赢得了战争
The war's not won. Not while Stannis lives.
只要史坦尼斯还活着，战争就还未胜利
I broke Stannis on the Blackwater.
我在黑水河之役击败了史坦尼斯
Pity you weren't there to help, Uncle.
可惜你不在那儿，帮不上忙，舅舅
My apologies, Your Grace. I was rather busy.
抱歉，陛下，我当时很忙
Busy getting captured.
忙着被抓呢
So this is the famous "Book of Brothers"?
这就是有名的“铁卫名册”？
All the great deeds of all the great Kingsguard.
御林铁卫的英雄事迹
Ser Arthur Dayne. The Sword of the Morning.
亚瑟·戴恩爵士，拂晓神剑
Led the attack on the Kingswood Brotherhood.
带领剿灭御林兄弟会
Defeated the Smiling Knight in single combat.
在决战中击败了微笑骑士
Ser Duncan the Tall.
高个邓肯爵士
Four pages for Ser Duncan.
邓肯爵士的事迹写了四页呢
He must have been quite a man.
他一定是个勇士
So they say.
他们是这么说
Ser Jaime Lannister.
詹姆·兰尼斯特爵士
Someone forgot to write down all your great deeds.
有人忘了把你的英雄事迹写上
- There's still time. - Is there?
- 来日方长
- 是吗？
For a 40-year-old knight with one hand?
四十岁的独臂骑士？
How can you protect me with that?
你这样还怎么保护我？
I use my left hand now, Your Grace.
我现在可以用左手，陛下
Makes for more of a contest.
更有竞争力
Have you ever been to Meereen?
你去过弥林吗？
Several times, Your Grace, with Master Kraznys.
去过几次，陛下，和克拉兹尼一起
And?
然后呢？
They say 1,000 slaves died
他们说在建造弥林大金字塔时
building the Great Pyramid of Meereen.
死了一千名奴隶
And now an army of former slaves
而现在，一支由之前的奴隶组成的军队
is marching to her gates.
正在向她的大门行进
You think the Great Masters are worried?
你觉得伟主们会担心吗？
If they're smart, Your Grace.
如果他们聪明的话，陛下
You were told to ride at the back of the train.
你应该跟在队伍的最后
Yes, my queen.
是的，我的女王
But I need to speak to you about something important.
但是我有重要的事情要对您说
A matter of strategy.
战略事务
Your Grace.
陛下
All right, what is this matter of strategy?
好吧，什么战略事务？
A dusk rose.
一支幽暗玫瑰
Would you like to walk at the back of the train instead of riding?
你是想在队伍最后跟着走吗？而不是骑马
And this one's called lady's lace.
这一支叫做女人的蕾丝
Would you like to walk without shoes?
你是想光脚走吗？
You have to know a land to rule it.
您应该了解要统治的地方
Its plants, its rivers,
那儿的植物，那儿的河流
its roads, its people.
那儿的道路，那儿的人民
Dusk rose tea eases fever.
幽暗玫瑰茶可以退烧
Everyone in Meereen knows that.
弥林的每个人都知道
Especially the slaves who have to make the tea.
尤其是要沏茶的奴隶
If you want them to follow you,
如果您希望他们跟随您
you have to become a part of their world.
您就要融入他们的世界
Strategy.
这就是战略
Harpy's Gold.
金鹰妖
No tea from this one.
这种花不能用来泡茶
Beautiful but poisonous.
美丽但有毒
You are a gambler, aren't you?
你确实是个赌徒，不是吗？
Your Grace.
陛下
There's one on every mile marker between here and Meereen.
从这儿到弥林每隔一里就有一个
How many miles are there between here and Meereen?
这里到弥林有多少里？
163, Your Grace.
163里，陛下
<i>I'll tell our men to ride</i> <i>ahead and bury them.</i>
<i>我会下令让人骑在前面，烧了她们</i>
You don't need to see this.
您不需要看到
You will do no such thing.
不能这么做
I will see each and every one of their faces.
我要看到她们每一个人的脸
Remove her collar before you bury her.
拿掉项圈，然后把她埋了
<i>There she is.</i>
<i>她在那儿</i>
Yes, there she is.
是的，她在那儿
- And? - You made a promise.
- 然后呢？
- 你保证过的
To return the Stark girls to their mother who is now dead.
把史塔克家的女儿还给她们死了的母亲
To keep them safe.
保证她们安全
Well, Arya Stark hasn't been seen since her father was killed.
自从艾莉亚·史塔克的父亲死后，再没人看见过她
Where do you think she is? My money's on dead.
你认为她在哪？我赌她已经死了
There's a certain safety in death, wouldn't you say?
死了也是种安全，你觉得呢？
And Sansa Stark is now Sansa Lannister.
珊莎·史塔克现在叫珊莎·兰尼斯特
Bit of a complication.
有点复杂
A complication does not release you from a vow.
再复杂也不能言而无信
What do you want me to do? Kidnap my sister-in-law?
你想要我怎样？绑架我的弟媳？
And take her where? Where would she be safer than here?
然后带她去哪？哪里会比这里安全？
Look me in the eye and tell me
看着我的眼睛告诉我…
that you think she'll be safe in King's Landing.
你认为她在君临会安全
Are you sure we're not related?
你确定…我们不是亲戚？
Ever since I've returned, every Lannister I've seen
自从我回来，我见到的每个兰尼斯特…
has been a miserable pain in my ass.
都在给我找麻烦
Maybe you're a Lannister, too.
也许你也是其中之一
You've got the hair for it if not the looks.
头发很像，样子差远了
It's all right.
没事的
It's all right. It's all right.
没事的，没事的
- You're drunk. - Yes.
- 你醉了
- 是的
I have good reason to be.
我喝醉是应该的
Once I was a knight. Now I'm only a fool.
我曾经是骑士，现在只是个弄臣
Don't you know me?
你不认识我？
Ser Dontos. The king's nameday celebration.
唐托斯爵士，在国王的命名日
I'm sorry. I should have remembered.
抱歉，我应该记得的
I can't accept your apology.
你不必道歉
I may be a fool, but I'm a living fool, thanks to you.
也许我是个小丑，但起码活着，谢谢你
Anyone would have done the same.
每个人都会这么做的
But only you did.
但只有你
I can never repay you.
我无法报答你
You gave me my life. But this,
我的命是你给的，但这个…
this is worth more than my life.
这个比我的命值钱
It belonged to my mother and her mother before her.
它曾经属于我的母亲，我母亲的母亲
House Hollard was strong once.
霍拉德家族曾经辉煌过
House on the rise.
崛起的家族
That's all that's left of those days,
但往昔只留下这个…
thanks to a few sad, fat drunks like me.
归功于几个像我一样可悲的酒鬼
I can't take it.
我不能收
It's very, very kind of you, but I can't.
非常非常感谢你，但我不能收
I don't have anything else left.
我没有别的东西了
That's all.
只有这个
Take it. Wear it.
收下吧，戴上它
Let my name have one more moment in the sun
让我的名字还能见到阳光
before it disappears from the world.
趁它还没有消失
I'll wear it with pride, Ser Dontos.
我会骄傲地戴着的，唐托斯爵士
Yeah.
行
<i>When am I going to get</i> <i>a horse of my own?</i>
<i>我什么时候才能有自己的马？</i>
The little lady wants a pony.
小女士想要匹马
The little lady wants away from your stench.
小女士想要远离你的臭味
Horses aren't easy to come by.
马可没那么容易搞到
Even if they were,
就算有…
you think I'm gonna put you on your own horse?
你以为我会让你自己骑？
Watch the only thing of value I've got in the world ride away?
让我唯一有价值的东西逃走？
Why don't you have any money?
你为什么没有钱？
Didn't you steal anything from Joffrey before you left?
你离开前不是偷了乔佛里的东西的？
No.
没有
You're not very smart, are you?
你不是很机灵，是吗？
I'm not a thief.
我不是小偷
You're fine with murdering little boys,
你杀小孩子没事…
but thieving is beneath you?
偷东西却不行？
A man's got to have a code.
做人要有原则
You think I'm gonna escape?
你以为我会逃走？
Where would I go?
我能去哪？
I'd be dead by nightfall without you.
没有你，天一黑我就没命了
My family's gone. I've got no one.
我的家族没了，我没人可以依靠
You've got an aunt in the Vale.
你在谷地还有个姨妈
Your rich Aunt Lysa. After I sell you to her,
你富有的莱莎姨妈，我把你卖给她
maybe she'll have enough left over
也许她还剩点钱…
to buy you that pony you want so much.
给你买匹你渴望的马
<i>I'm hungry.</i> <i>You're hungry.</i>
<i>我饿了，你也饿了</i>
Five horses, five men.
五匹马，五个人
More than I feel like killing on an empty stomach.
空着肚子，我杀不了这么多
I know him.
我认识他
<i>The small one.</i> <i>His name is Polliver.</i>
<i>那个小个子，他叫波利佛</i>
He captured us and took us to Harrenhal.
他抓住了我们，带我们去了赫伦堡
He killed Lommy.
他杀了罗米
What the fuck's a Lommy?
罗米他妈是谁？
He was my friend.
他是我朋友
Polliver stole my sword and put it right through his neck.
波利佛偷了我的剑，刺穿了他的脖子
He's still got it.
他还带着
<i>Got what?</i>
<i>带着什么？</i>
My sword Needle.
我的剑，缝衣针
Needle? Of course you named your sword.
缝衣针？一定是你命名的
Lots of people name their swords.
很多人都给自己的剑命名
Lots of cunts.
很多傻子
What are you-- get back here.
你在干…快回来
My brother gave me that sword.
这剑是我哥哥给的
- Get back here. - He killed my friend.
- 快回来
- 他杀了我朋友
I don't care if he ate your friend.
他吃了你朋友我也不管
We're not going in there.
我们不要进去
<i>Come on, give it up.</i>
<i>过来，你就从了吧</i>
Come here.
过来
- Let's have a feel there. - Leave it.
- 让我摸摸那里
- 等下
Come here.
过来
Please, she's a good girl.
求你了，她是好姑娘
Shut your mouth and pour us more ale
闭嘴，给我们倒酒
and we may not take her with us when we're done with her.
我们搞完了，兴许把她留下
I know you.
我认识你
You're the Hound.
你是猎狗
<i>Pour our new friend</i> <i>some ale.</i>
<i>给我们的新朋友倒点酒</i>
What brings you so far north?
什么风把你吹到这么北的地方？
I could ask the same of you.
我还想问你呢
What are you doing up here?
你在这里干嘛？
Just keeping the king's peace.
维持王国的和平
No need. The war's over.
没必要，战争结束了
So I've heard. Stannis defeated at the Blackwater.
我听说了，史坦尼斯在黑水河被击溃
Robb Stark killed at the Twins.
罗柏·史塔克在孪河城被杀
And where am I for all of it?
我在干嘛？
Stuck with your brother.
跟你哥哥混在一起
- Meaning no offense. - None taken.
- 我没有恶意
- 没关系
He's good, the Mountain is.
他不错，我说魔山
Best at what he does.
顶尖高手
But torture, torture, torture, torture.
但就是酷刑、酷刑、酷刑、酷刑
<i>You spend enough time putting</i> <i>the hammer to people,</i>
<i>老用锤子去打人…</i>
<i>you start to feel like</i> <i>a carpenter making chairs.</i>
<i>你会感觉像个木匠在做椅子</i>
Drains the fun right out of it.
毫无乐趣可言
And what's life without a little fun?
没乐趣干嘛还活着？
But I don't need to tell you that, eh?
这一点不用我说
She's all right. I've had better.
她还可以，我有过更好的
You know what?
你知道吗？
You should come with us.
你该跟我们一起走
His kind, they've always got something hidden away somewhere.
他这种人，总是藏了些东西
Gold, silver, more daughters.
金子，银子，女儿
<i>Always something if you</i> <i>know how to make them talk.</i>
<i>只要让他们开口，总有些东西</i>
And there's plenty of him between here and King's Landing.
从这里到君临城有很多这样的人
You could do well for yourself.
你可以发笔小财
We certainly have been.
我们已经发了
I'm not going to King's Landing.
我不去君临城
Think about it. We could do whatever we like
想想吧，我们可以为所欲为
wherever we go.
畅通无阻
These are the king's colors.
这是国王的颜色
No one's standing in his way now.
没人敢反抗他
Which means no one's standing in ours.
也就是说，没人敢反抗我们
Fuck the king.
操国王他妈
When I heard that Joffrey's dog had tucked tail
我听说乔佛里的狗夹着尾巴…
and run from the Battle of the Blackwater,
逃离了黑水河之战
I didn't believe it.
我还不信
- But here you are. - Here I am.
- 但你就在这里
- 我在这里
Bring me one of those chickens.
给我拿只鸡
- You got money to pay for it? - You paid for it?
- 你有钱吗？
- 你给钱了？
No.
没有
But we're the king's men.
但我们是国王的人
So, you got money?
你有钱吗？
Not a penny.
一个子儿也没有
I'll still take that chicken.
我还是要那只鸡
Tell you what.
这么说吧
We'll trade you.
我跟你换
One of our little chickens for one of yours.
我的一只鸡换你的一只鸡
<i>Give us a go</i> <i>at your friend.</i>
<i>把你的朋友给我们</i>
Lowell there likes them a bit broken in.
那边的洛威尔喜欢旧货
You're a talker.
你真能说
Listening to talkers makes me thirsty.
听能说的人讲话我就渴了
And hungry.
也饿了
Think I'll take two chickens.
我要两只鸡
You don't seem to understand the situation.
你还搞不清楚状况
I understand that if any more words
我很清楚，再有一句话…
come pouring out of your cunt mouth,
从你脸上的屁眼里出来
I'm gonna have to eat every fucking chicken in this room.
我就吃光这屋里所有的鸡
You lived your life for the king.
你为国王而活
You're gonna die for some chickens?
就为了几只鸡寻死？
Someone is.
有人会死
Something wrong with your leg, boy?
你腿有问题吗，小子？
What? What do you mean?
什么？你什么意思？
Can you walk? I've got to carry you?
你能走吗？我得背着你？
Carry me?
背着我？
Fine little blade.
这把小剑还真不错
Maybe I'll pick my teeth with it.
也许我会拿来剔牙
-=TLF字幕组=-
谢谢观赏
TLF中文字幕站 http://sub.eastgame.org/
微博地址：http://t.sina.com.cn/tlfsubs
豆瓣小站：http://site.douban.com/127446/